

1404-128 W. Cordova St. Vancouver BC V6B 0E6

□ 778-558-3029 | ■ bollain@gmail.com | 🎓 www.armandodb.com | 🖸 bollain | 🛅 Armando Bollain

## **Summary**

Highly professional team player with a passion for new tech and clean code. Interested in web development, distributed systems, and infrastructure. Looking for an opportunity to work in a challenging environment where I will be able to make meaningful contributions and continue to master my craft. Graduate of the University of British Columbia's second degree program in Computer Science after 5+ years working in the finance industry.

## Skills

**Programming** JavaScript, C#, C, Java, Go, Swift, SQL

> IDE Visual Studio, IntelliJ, Xcode

**Operating Systems** Linux, OSX, Windows

> Web Rails, Node.js, Swagger, Express, React, HTML5, SASS

Languages English, Spanish

## Education

#### **University of British Columbia**

BACHELOR IN COMPUTER SCIENCE, GPA: 83%

• Co-operative Education Designation

### **Thompson Rivers University**

**BACHELOR IN BUSINESS ADMINISTRATION** 

Honours

• Major in Finance, Minor in Economics

Vancouver, British Columbia

Sept. 2014 - Dec. 2017

Kamloops, British Columbia

Sept. 2004 - Apr. 2008

May 2017 - September 2017

# Work Experience \_\_

**Vision Critical** Vancouver, British Columbia

RELEASE ENGINEERING CO-OP • Member of a team responsible for creating the tools that facilitated regularly scheduled releases to production.

- Implemented a tool written in Golang to populate production secrets from Vault.
- Worked on a tool that published build artifacts to Amazon's S3 during releases.

**Vision Critical** Vancouver, British Columbia January 2016 - December 2016

SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT CO-OP

· Member of the development team responsible for overhauling the client-facing reporting solution for a legacy application.

- Developed new visualizations using React and Redux as well as the REST endpoints they consumed.
- Implemented a new feature that allowed users to synch data directly from the reports, replacing an antiquated workflow. This involved the creation of new REST API endpoints, and working closely with the UX team to get the right look and feel for the new feature.

**CIBC Lending & Credit** Vancouver, British Columbia

INTERMEDIATE UNDERWRITER

March 2013 - July 2014

- Responsible for underwriting residential mortgages in Western Canada with a personal lending authority of \$1.5M.
- Consistently met & exceeded productivity goals, maintaining a high level of service with our clients and business partners.

**GE Capital** Vancouver, British Columbia

UNDERWRITER

September 2008 - March 2013

• Underwrote commercial credit applications of up to \$5M for companies working in the construction, forestry and oil & gas sector in Western Canada.

FEBRUARY 14, 2018 ARMANDO BOLLAIN · RÉSUMÉ

# **Personal Projects**

Inukshuk Jan. 2017 - Ongoing

- Application that allows users to set up alerts before they go on hikes. If they don't return by a certain time, automated text messages are sent to the emergency contact with the last known GPS location of user.
- Developed using React-Native with a Node.js back-end.
- · Main tasks included integrating SMS alerts with Twilio and implementing a REST API that was fully documented using Swagger.
- Live API hosted on a Raspberry Pi: http://www.roastery.me:1985/docs/
- App promo video: https://youtu.be/qVtyLHlWd11

Ride the Buzz November 2015

- · Webapp that allows users to set SMS alerts to let them know when their bus is nearing their preferred stop.
- · Built using Ruby on Rails, integrating with Twilio's API for text messages and Translink's API for real time bus locations.

H2Go July 2015

- Webapp that maps drinking fountains and bike racks in the City of Vancouver based on a user's location.
- Developed using Ruby on Rails as part of a 5-week course in software engineering, following agile methodologies (https://h2go.herokuapp.com/)

BeerApp March 2015

- Command line application that allows users to find the perfect food pairing for their favourite brew.
- Written in Java, leveraging multiple 3rd party APIs.